Boss!
お… 御頭！
申し訳ありませぬ！
I apologize!
御頭の友人とは つゆしらず
とんだご無礼を！
We didn't realize they were your
friends and mistreated them!
Who's the guy with the stony face?
(銀時)だ… 誰だ｡ あの公家顔｡
(外道丸)晴明様でござんす｡
Lord Seimei.
Head of the Ketsuno clan.
結野衆頭目 一族歴代最強を
うたわれる 天才陰陽師➡
A genius onmyoji who's said to
be the strongest in clan history.
結野晴明｡
Seimei Ketsuno.
[Note: Based off the Onmyoji Seimei Abeno.]
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様の兄上でござんす｡
へ？
Lady Christel's older brother.
Huh?
["Not Losing to the Wind"]
I apologize for the uncomfortable experience.
(晴明)嫌な思いをさせて
すまなんだな｡
外道丸 よくぞｸﾘｽﾃﾙの
友人たちを護ってくれた｡
Gedomaru, you did well to
protect Christel's friends.
礼を言うぞ｡
You have my gratitude.
(晴明)気のすむまで
ゆっくりしてゆくがよい｡
Please rest to your heart's content.
このまま帰しては
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙに どやされるからのう｡
Christel will yell at me if I allow you to
leave without offering any hospitality.
I can also serve liquor if any of you drink.
(晴明)
いけるｸﾁなら酒も出すが｡
He made a feast appear with
a snap of his fingers.
(新八)ゆ 指ﾊﾟｯﾁﾝひとつで
ご馳走出した！
He's a monster!
ば… 化け物だ！
ﾎﾟｰﾙ牧の化け物だ！
A Paul Maki monster!
[Note: Japanese Comedian who was popular
with his constant finger snaps.]
ぎ… 銀さん｡
もう 頭が変になりそうですよ｡
Gin-san, I think I'm going crazy!
ﾎﾞｸら 狐につままれてるんですよ｡
We've got fox spirits wrapped around us!
つままれてるどころの
騒ぎじゃねえぞ｡
Wrapped around us?
もうずっと 乳首つままれて
ｺﾘｺﾘやられてる気分だ｡
More like they've been
suckling at our nipples.
よもや 本当に
化生の仕業かもしれやせん｡
This may be the work of a devil.
I shall test it for poison first.
まずは あっしが
毒見するでござんす｡
おい よだれ出てんぞ｡
Hey, you're drooling.
That's mine!
Uh, Seimei-san...
(神楽)それは 私んだ!!
あの… 晴明さん｡
なんで ﾎﾞｸらが結野ｱﾅの知り合い
だってわかったんですか？
How did you know we were acquainted
with Ms. Ketsuno?
We of the Ketsuno clan have used
our knowledge of Onmyodo
我ら 結野衆
陰陽道によって➡
長きにわたり
幕府と江戸を護ってきた｡
to defend the Bakufu and
Edo for a long time.
ならば どのような
手段をもってして➡
Do you know how we have
carried out that duty?
それらの使命を
まっとうしているか わかるか？
Through our sight.
見ることじゃ｡
Give it to me!
災厄 凶兆を占うといっても➡
When foretelling disaster or ill omens,
まずは 対象をあらゆる角度から
見つめ 分析しなければ➡
one must first analyze the target from every
possible angle in order to see anything.
何も見えてこん｡
(晴明)この江戸の街には
ﾜｼが放った 無数の式神が➡
I have stationed shikigami all around
Edo to serve as my eyes.
その目を光らせているのじゃ｡
そこから得た
無数の情景から➡
It is my duty to process the
information they send,
国家の行く末 幕府の進むべき
道を導き出すのが➡
determine what direction this nation is heading,
and how the Bakufu should act.
ﾜｼの務めよ｡
そのﾜｼが 妹１人のことさえ
把握していないとでも？
How could I not be aware
of my sister's situation?
Heh. I see that Big Bro knows
everything that's going on.
ﾌｯ｡ どうやらお兄さんは
すべて お見通しのようだな｡
だったら 話が早え｡
That makes this simple.
ﾃﾒｴら 結野ｱﾅに
いったい 何しやがった｡
What did you people do to Ms. Ketsuno?
You believe that we are the reason Christel
can no longer forecast the weather?
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙが 天気を
読めなくなったのは➡
ﾜｼらの仕業だと？
最強の陰陽師とやらなら
それも可能なんじゃねえのか？
Wouldn't the strongest onmyoji ever
be capable of such a thing?
It's true that when Christel left the
Ketsuno clan without a word
(晴明)確かに ｸﾘｽﾃﾙが
結野衆を黙って抜け➡
その力を
市井で使い出したとき➡
and chose to use her power
for the common people,
格式ばった連中は
それに反対した｡
the traditionalists were
vehemently opposed.
かくいうﾜｼも そのｸﾁじゃ｡
あの姿を見るまでは…｡
I was also one of them
until I saw her as...
Boss!
御頭!!
まさか… ちっ｡
Could it be?!
Wait! Seimei-san, where are you going?!
ちょ… 晴明さんどこへ？
(結野)朝は 予報はずしちゃって
ごめんなさい｡
I apologize for being off with
the morning forecast.
気持を切り替えて お昼からの天気
お伝えしたいと思います｡
I hope to do better as I give
you the afternoon forecast.
Christel!
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ!!
Why?! Why is Christel, morning personality,
reporting a daytime weather forecast?!
なぜじゃ！ なぜ朝の顔のｸﾘｽﾃﾙが
昼間のﾃﾚﾋﾞに出ておる!!
御頭！ それが予定していた
別のお天気お姉さんが➡
Boss! That's because the other weather
lady got sick and took the day off.
ｶｾﾞで休んだらしくて｡
Just hurry!
いいから 早く！
早く DVDに録画を！
Hurry up and record this on DVD!
それが 御頭
DVDの容量が➡
But boss!
The disk is full after recording
Spider-man yesterday!
昨日撮った
ｽﾊﾟｲﾀﾞｰﾏﾝで ﾊﾟﾝﾊﾟﾝです！
Erase it!
(晴明)消せ！ ｽﾊﾟｲﾀﾞｰﾏﾝ消せ！
もう何回も見たし！
Erase Spider-man!
We've already seen it so many times!
No, we can't!
やっぱﾀﾞﾒ｡ ｷﾝｸﾞｺﾝ…｡
やっぱ ｽﾊﾟｲﾀﾞｰﾏﾝ｡
Erase King Kong...
No, stick to Spider-man!
Just erase the parts where
the heroine shows up!
ｽﾊﾟｲﾀﾞｰﾏﾝの
ﾋﾛｲﾝのところだけ消せ！
あの腹立つ！
The annoying one!
それでは いきま～す！
Here I go then!
Boss! Her forecast is starting!
御頭 予報始まっちゃってます！
Hey! You bastards ready to pray?!
おい ｷｻﾏら！
祈祷の用意はできたか！
聞き逃すなよ ｷｻﾏら！
Don't miss what she says!
なんとしても ｸﾘｽﾃﾙの
予報を当てさせるんじゃ!!
We'll do whatever it takes to make
Christel's forecast accurate!
言った瞬間祈れよ!!
間髪入れずに祈れよ!!
Pray the second she speaks!
The very instant she speaks!
(一同)はっ!!
Yes, sir!
[ﾓﾆﾀ](結野)江戸一帯の
今日の昼からの天気は…｡
The afternoon forecast for Edo...
(結野)晴れです｡
(晴明)晴れろ!!
Is sunny.
Make it sunny!
Gin-san, the entire clan is supporting
her, not interfering.
銀さん ｼﾞｬﾏするどころか
一族あげて応援してますけど｡
晴明さん 妹萌えどころか
妹燃やしそうな勢いなんですけど｡
Seimei-san seems about ready
to literally burn up for his sister.
新八 ﾑﾀﾞｱﾙ｡
ｱｲﾂももう 一族の一員ね｡
Shinpachi, it's no use.
He already joined their family.
Say, why is the person who was
suspecting them joining in?!
ねえ なんで さっきまで
ここの人疑ってた人が➡
なんで あんなことできるの!?
なんで あんなに自然に➡
How can he blend in so perfectly?!
溶け込めるの!?
あ… あれは…｡
What is that?!
やはり ﾔﾂらも…
負けるな 者ども！
So they've also begun!
Don't give in, men!
ﾔﾂらの呪法を打ち消してやれ！
うお～!!
Break their spell!
The two sides are pushing and prancing
around with each other.
あっちとこっちで押し合って
踊り狂ってるｱﾙ！
(外道丸)巳厘野家でござんす｡
巳厘野家？
It is the Shirino clan.
Shirino clan?
(外道丸)結野と双璧をなす
陰陽師一族｡ それが巳厘野家｡
A family of onmyoji that
rivals the Ketsuno.
The Shirino clan.
平安の頃より
結野家と巳厘野家は➡
The Ketsuno clan and Shirino clan
熾烈な権力争いを
繰り広げ続けてきた➡
have been in a savage struggle for political
power since the Heian period.
犬猿の仲なのでござんす｡
なんで そんな仲悪いのが
お隣さんに住んでんの～!!
If they hate each other so much, why
do they live next to each other?!
長らく争ってきた
結野家と巳厘野家は➡
After many years of fighting,
この江戸の時勢において初めて➡
they finally joined to serve the Bakufu
together in this Edo period.
ともに幕府に
めしかかえられるという➡
偉業をなしとげたでやんす｡
清明様の手によって｡
Through Lord Seimei's efforts.
だが…
新たな悲劇が生まれてしまった｡
However, a new tragedy was born.
平和協定を申し入れた清明様に➡
The Shirino clan placed one condition
in the peace accord.
巳厘野家が提案した
条件は１つでやんした…｡
To offer Lady Christel as a bride.
｢ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様を嫁によこせ｣と…｡
《それって あのときの…》
Is that when...
(([ﾓﾆﾀ]お天気お姉さんとして
人気を博した結野ｱﾅが➡
Ms. Ketsuno, known to everyone as the
weather lady, has gotten married.
結婚していたことが
わかりました))
当時の清明様は➡
Lord Seimei accepted the condition,
believing that it would serve to bring
Lady Christel back to this world.
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様を
こちらの世界に戻すいい機会と➡
この条件をのみやした｡
そして ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様もまた➡
And Lady Christel also agreed,
両家の平和のためならと
嫁いだのでござんす｡
believing it would make peace
between the clans.
しかし 本心までは
偽ることはできやせん｡
However, she was unable
to lie to herself.
嫁いだあとは 日を追うごとに
やせ衰えていき…｡
After getting married,
she grew weaker every day.
あの頃のｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様は
空ばかり眺めていたでござんす｡
Lady Christel spent most of her time
gazing into the sky back then.
Once Lord Seimei saw her,
he realized his mistake,
その姿を見て
自分の愚に気づいた清明様は…｡
broke the peace accord,
got Lady Christel divorced,
(外道丸)平和協定を捨て
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様を離縁させ➡
お天気ｱﾅへと
復帰させたのでござんす｡
and returned her to her position
as weather lady.
あとに残ったのは 形だけ無様に
仲よく隣に並んだ➡
Leaving two clans, allies only in name,
serving the Bakufu side-by-side...
幕府の役職と この屋敷…｡
And the hatred was greater than before.
そして前より より強くなった
強き怨嗟の念でござんす｡
The emotions of the two clans towards
Lady Christel were tangled up,
(外道丸)両家の思いは
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様を介し➡
複雑に絡み合い 戦いは➡
and their battle grew into something
never seen before.
過去 類を見ない苛烈なものへと
変わってしまいやした｡
A mystic battle.
(外道丸)呪法合戦｡
お天気戦争でござんす｡
Over the weather.
So the ones who messed
そ… それじゃあ 結野ｱﾅの
天気予報をはずさせ 彼女を➡
with Ms. Ketsuno's weather forecast
and got her fired are...
お天気お姉さんから 引きずり
おろそうとしてるってのは…｡
Boss! We can't hold on much longer!
御頭！ もっ…
もう これ以上もちません！
こらえろ！
必ず天気を晴れにするんだ！
Stand strong!
We must make it sunny!
ぐあ～！ もっ… もう ﾀﾞﾒだ～!!
We can't hold on!
Guys!
み… みんな！
そう…
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様にふりかかる災いは➡
Yes...
The misfortune which has befallen Lady
Christel is the work of a single man.
すべて １人の男の
呪法によって もたらされたもの｡
巳厘野衆頭目 ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様の元旦那｡
The head of the Shirino clan,
Lady Christel's ex-husband.
黒き陰陽師…
巳厘野道満でござんす｡
The black onmyoji, Doman Shirino.
[Based off Doman Ashiya, Seimei's rival.]
That's Ms. Ketsuno's...
あれが 結野ｱﾅの…｡
元旦那さん…｡
Ex-husband...?
Yes, though they were married,
そう… 結婚したとはいえ
まったく心も開かれず➡
they never opened up to one
another or held hands,
手も握らないまま
清明様に妻を奪われた男…｡
before Lord Seimei
stole his wife away.
道満…｡
Doman...
(道満)ｸｸｸ… ｱｰｯﾊﾊ！
Seimei, it appears that I win again!
清明 どうやら今日も
ｵﾚの勝ちのようだな！
また はずれてしまったな｡
妹の天気予報｡
Your sister's weather forecast is wrong.
She should quit before they force her off.
降板を待たずして
辞めてしまえばいいものを｡
天気も当てられぬというのに
のうのうとﾃﾚﾋﾞに出続けるとは｡
How does she have the nerve to appear on
television with her inaccurate forecasts...
兄妹揃って
ﾂﾗの皮だけは厚いらしい｡
I see that both siblings are thick-skinned.
道満 ｷｻﾏ～！
Doman, damn you...
はぁ～!!
Circular flyer!
回覧版じゃ～!!
なに!?
What?!
ｸｸ… 清明 最強の陰陽師の名を
ほしいままにしてきた➡
Seimei, you may strive to
be the greatest onmyoji,
お前の呪法とて もはやｵﾚに➡
but your abilities are no longer
able to even scratch me.
かすり傷ひとつ
負わすことは叶わん｡
ほう 町内会 秋の松茸狩り旅行か｡
Oh, a neighborhood matsutake-picking trip.
どうしようかな？
Should I participate?
ｵﾚは もう 昔のｵﾚではない｡
I am no longer the person I was before.
ｷｻﾏら兄妹に復讐せんがため
生まれ変わったんだよ｡
I was reborn to extract revenge
against you siblings.
清明 お前は欠席か｡
Seimei, you won't be participating?
ならば ｵﾚは出てやる ｻﾞﾏｰﾐﾛ｡
Then I'm going, up yours.
ｷｻﾏ…｡
Bastard...
After challenging and being defeated
by the Shirino clan multiple times,
我ら
巳厘野衆に はむかうにも➡
幾度の呪法合戦に敗れ➡
もはや お前のもとに
戦える者などおるまい｡
you no longer have anyone able to fight.
You are the only one left
to protect your sister.
妹を護る盾は もうお前だけだ｡
This rain will never end, Seimei.
雨は やまぬぞ｡ 清明…｡
たとえ ｸﾘｽﾃﾙが
お天気お姉さんをｸﾋﾞになろうと➡
Christel may be fired from her
position as weather lady...
ｷｻﾏら 結野家が滅亡しようと➡
The Ketsuno clan may be obliterated...
もう この雨は やまん｡
And this rain will still continue.
ｷｻﾏら兄妹の慟哭を消し去るまで➡
This rain will continue until the wails
of you siblings have forever ceased.
この雨は 降り続くのだ｡
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
これ
隣の岩下さんちに回しといて｡
Pass this to Iwashita-san
next door, will ya?
清明さん！
(神楽)しっかりするね！ 妹萌え！
Seimei-san!
Get a grip, sister lover!
まさか 天気を左右する争いが➡
I never imagined that a battle over
the weather was taking place.
こんなところで
行われていたなんて…｡
ご近所ﾄﾗﾌﾞﾙも 陰陽師となると➡
An argument between neighbors gets blown
out of proportion when onmyoji are involved.
こんなに
大変なことになるんですね｡
みんな やられちゃったｱﾙ｡
They were all beaten up.
外道丸さん…｡
Gedomaru-san, Ms. Ketsuno doesn't
know about this, does she?
結野ｱﾅは このこと
知らないんですよね｡
あっしが情報を
ｼｬｯﾄｱｳﾄしたでござんす｡
I've been keeping her out of the loop.
え？
なんでｱﾙか？
Huh?
Why's that?!
結野ｱﾅ
あんなに苦しんでたのに！
Ms. Ketsuno was suffering so much!
この騒ぎを知れば
事を治めようとして➡
If she knew about this fight,
また 道満のもとへ
行こうとするでござんす｡
she would return to Doman in
an attempt to end the fight.
両家の争いなど
正直どうでもようござんす｡
Quite frankly, I don't give a damn about
this battle between the clans.
あっしを調伏し
こき使う結野家など➡
I couldn't care less if the Ketsuno clan, which
tamed and used me, were to be crushed.
潰れても一向に構いやせん｡
But...
でも ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様の➡
I never want to see Lady Christel
look so sorrowful again.
あんな寂しそうな顔を見るのは
もう ごめんでござんす｡
You really care about
Ms. Ketsuno, don't you?
大事に思ってるんですね｡
結野ｱﾅのこと｡
Lady Christel was the only onmyoji master
who ever treated me as a friend.
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様は あっしが仕えた
陰陽師の中で唯一➡
友人のように
接してくれた方でござんすから｡
それに あの方も
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様に事が知れるのは➡
And he does not wish for Lady
Christel to learn the truth.
本意ではないでしょう｡
Hello, Ketsuno here.
ﾊｰｲ 結野です｡
昼間は また予報をはずしちゃって
ごめんなさい｡
I apologize for being wrong with
my afternoon forecast, too.
明日の天気こそは 必ず…
I promise to do better tomorrow.
Shut up!
うるせえ!! 何回 天気はずしたら
気がすむんだ｡ 小娘！
How many times are you going
to screw up the forecast, girl?
あっ ちょっと 撮影中ですから！
Ah, excuse me.
Camera's rolling.
Who gives a damn?
何が撮影中だ！
当たらねえ天気予報なんか➡
Stop giving forecasts that are wrong!
やめちまえ！
そうだ そうだ！
Yeah! Yeah!
Nobody's watching your
forecasts anymore!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]お前の天気予報なんて
もう誰も見ちゃいねえんだよ！
[ﾓﾆﾀ]物を投げるのは
やめてください！
Please stop throwing things!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]結野ｱﾅ 逃げて！ 危ない！
Ms. Ketsuno, run! It's dangerous here!
[ﾓﾆﾀ](結野)それでは
これからの天気をお伝えします｡
Then I'll be giving the forecast now.
[ﾓﾆﾀ]ちょっと何やってんの 結野ｱﾅ｡
危ないってば！
Wait! What are you doing, Ketsuno?!
It's dangerous!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]あぁ 大丈夫？ 結野ｱﾅ！
The hell?
Are you okay, Ms. Ketsuno?!
[ﾓﾆﾀ]やめろ やめろ！
ぬし… ｸﾘｽﾃﾙのﾌｧﾝなのじゃろ｡
Aren't you a fan of Christel?
よくも見れたものだな｡
I can't believe you can watch this.
あぁ ｵﾚ ドＳなもんで｡ それに➡
Yeah, I'm a super sadist.
Besides...
結野ｱﾅが耐えてんだから｡
Ms. Ketsuno is putting up with
this crap to give her report.
It isn't known when this rain will
end, but by tomorrow morning...
それでも
伝えようとしてんだから｡
見なきゃいけねえでしょう
ｵﾚたちも｡
We have a duty to watch.
Isn't that right, big brother?
ねぇ お兄様｡
誰が お兄様じゃ｡
Who are you calling your big brother?
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙを かような目に
あわせているのも➡
I am the one responsible
for Christel's suffering
道満を
闇の道へといざなったのも➡
and Doman's turning
down a dark path.
このﾜｼの仕業じゃ｡
ﾜｼが 目を背けてはいかぬな｡
I am not allowed to avert my eyes.
しっかりと 己の目で見なければ｡
I am obligated to watch every second.
以前のﾜｼは 結野衆頭目として
お家を護ろうとするあまり➡
In the past,
I was so focused on protecting the family
as the leader of the Ketsuno clan,
その使命に目がくらんでおった｡
that I allowed duty to blind
me to everything else.
I selfishly used my own sister as a tool
自分勝手に妹を
政治の道具に使い➡
自分勝手に
道満から それを奪った｡
before selfishly taking her
away from Doman.
すべてを見通し 江戸を護ってきた
最強の陰陽師が➡
Pathetic for the greatest onmyoji, who,
supposedly saw all as he defended Edo.
聞いて呆れるじゃろ？
誤って 初めて見えた｡
Only after blundering was I able to see.
失って 初めて見えた｡
Only after suffering loss was
I able to understand.
大切なものは
この両の目で見据えねば➡
You must watch the things that are
important with your own two eyes.
見えやしないのじゃ｡
兄上｡
Dear brother, what's that?
ｿｲﾂは 何ですか？
Who are you calling your dear brother?
誰が 兄上じゃ｡
道満から送られてきた書状じゃ｡
A letter sent from Doman.
(道満)｢晴明よ｡
Seimei, you should know well that continued
skirmishes will only serve to waste our men.
くだらん小競り合いを
繰り広げたところで➡
いたずらに 兵を
浪費するだけなのは➡
ｷｻﾏがいちばん 存じておろう｡
It is the duty of the head
to defend the family.
お家を護るのが 当主のつとめ｡
さりとて 妹を護るのも
兄のつとめ｡
And it is the duty of an older brother
to defend a younger sister.
どちらか一つを選べとは言わぬ｡
I won't tell you to choose between them.
もし ｷｻﾏが
両者を護りたいのであれば➡
If you wish to defend both,
face me in a contest.
我と 勝負せよ｣｡
In a Shikigami Tag Team
Mystic Deathmatch!
(道満)式神ﾀｯｸﾞ呪法ﾃﾞｽﾏｯﾁ！
(道満)この勝負をもって➡
This contest shall serve as the
final battle of the weather war!
お天気戦争が
決戦としようではないか！
Shikigami Tag Team
Mystic Deathmatch?
式神ﾀｯｸﾞ呪法ﾃﾞｽﾏｯﾁ？
なんですか？ こりゃ｡ にぃにぃ｡
The hell is that, broseph?
Who are you calling your broseph?
誰が にぃにぃじゃ｡
It refers to a 3-on-3 onmyodo match.
陰陽道における
３対３の決戦方式のことよ｡
なるほど｡ 果たし状ってわけか｡
I see. So this is a challenge.
結野ｱﾅだけじゃ 飽き足らず➡
So he isn't satisfied by
pestering Ms. Ketsuno.
ｵﾆｲﾀﾏまで
直接 潰しにかかってきたか…｡
He's come to directly crush bro-bro.
誰が ｵﾆｲﾀﾏじゃ！
おい いいかげんにせい！
Who are you calling your bro-bro?
Cut that out already!
どんだけ親族に
食い込もうとしとるんじゃ！
How desperate are you
to join my family?
No, I don't really mean anything by it.
いや 他意はありませんよ｡
ある日 突然
12人の かわいい弟に囲まれて➡
I just wanted to let you feel as though
you'd suddenly discovered
生活することになった気分を➡
that you were about to live with
twelve adorable little brothers.
味わってもらおうとしてるだけで｡
That's one creepy-as-hell
Brother Princess!
なに その 気持悪いﾌﾞﾗｻﾞｰﾌﾟﾘﾝｾｽ！
あっ！ やっぱり
知ってるんですね｡ ｼｽﾀｰﾌﾟﾘﾝｾｽ！
Oh, so you do know Sister Princess.
[Note: Sister Princess is a popular beautiful girls
novel, manga, anime and game franchise.]
やっぱ 妹萌えですか？ たまたま｡
たまたまって何？
So you do have a thing
for little sisters, ro-ro.
What the hell is ro-ro?
What does that have
to do with anything?
いったい どういう関係性!?
In any case, I believe this challenge
to be an opportunity.
とにかくだ｡ この果たし状は
ﾜｼは 一つのﾁｬﾝｽだと思っておる｡
勝てば
ﾌﾟﾘﾝｾｽｸﾘｽﾃﾙを救うことができる！
If I win, I can save Princess Christel.
That would be like walking
right into a trap, nutbro.
罠に飛び込むようなもんですよ｡
たまきん兄さん｡
たまきん兄さんって なに!?
The hell is a nutbro?
That makes it sound like I'm a nutxxxx!
もはや たまきんの兄さんに
なってるよね!? それ！
ﾜｼ１人で十分じゃ｡
I will accept the challenge alone.
この件はすべて ﾜｼに責任がある｡
The responsibility is all mine.
そこまでして
結野ｱﾅ 護ろうとしてんのは➡
Are you protecting Ms. Ketsuno
because you feel guilty?
その負い目のためなのか？
負い目か…｡
Guilt...?
いや… ただ
うらやましかったのかもしれぬ｡
No, I may have been jealous.
幕府のために
己の格式を護るためだけに➡
Here I was, using my power for the
Bakufu, to protect our traditions,
力を振るう ﾜｼに比べ➡
while she was using her power
to give people the weather.
人々に 天気を伝えるために➡
生き生きと 力を使うｱｲﾂが…｡
雨の日も 風の日も➡
As I watched her smile on rainy days and
windy days, I couldn't help but think...
笑顔を振りまき 天気を伝える
ｱｲﾂを見て思ったんじゃ…｡
ｱｲﾂは立派に 江戸を…➡
That she was doing a magnificent job
of protecting the people of Edo,
人々を… その手で護っている｡
幸せに導いている｡
of bringing them happiness...
ﾜｼなんぞより よっぽど偉大な
陰陽師なんじゃと…｡
She was a much greater onmyoji
than I could ever be...
ｱｲﾂはな…➡
She is...
My... Our clan's...
ﾜｼの… ﾜｼら結野衆の…➡
Pride and joy...
誇りなんじゃ…｡
やむかね？ 雨は…｡
I wonder if the rain will stop.
さぁ…｡ あいにく あっしは➡
Beats me.
Sadly, I don't know how
to read the heavens.
天道は読めないでござんすから｡
ただ これだけは言える｡
But there's one thing I can say.
晴明様は 死ぬでござんす｡
Lord Seimei will die.
(外道丸)道満は 以前より➡
Doman has become exponentially
stronger than before.
数段 強くなっておるでござんす｡
The mark on his face...
顔に刻まれた呪印…｡
おそらく 晴明様に勝つために
外法に 手を出したかと…｡
He must have dabbled in forbidden
arts so he could defeat Lord Seimei.
かわって 晴明様は➡
On the other hand, Lord Seimei has dispatched
countless shikigami to watch over Edo
無数の式神を 江戸守護に配し➡
力を 分散しているでござんす｡
and his power is dispersed.
He might have a chance if he
were to focus his power,
一つ所に 力を集めれば
わかりやせんが➡
役職上 それはできやせん｡
but his duty will not allow that to happen.
あの状態では 今の道満には
勝てないでござんす｡
He won't be able to defeat
Doman as things stand.
ｵﾚたちが行けば
ｿｲﾂは変わるのか？
Will that change if we go?
銀時様 こう言っちゃなんですが➡
Master Gintoki.
I didn't want to say this,
but you should butt out.
これ以上 この件に深入りするのは
よしなんせ｡
あっしが なぜ
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様につかわされたのか➡
Do you know why Lady
Christel sent me?
わかりやすか？
To stop you.
あなたたちを
止めるためでござんす｡
決して危険を犯させるな｡
I was ordered to keep you out of danger
彼らの命を
最優先に行動しろと命じられ➡
and prioritize your lives.
That can't be!
そんな このまま清明さんを
見殺しにしろってんですか!?
Are you telling us to stand by
and let Seimei-san die?!
We're the only ones left who can fight!
もう戦えるのは
ﾎﾞｸら以外いないんですよ！
Don't you realize who will grieve the
most if sister lover dies, bob cut?!
妹萌えが死んだら
誰が一番 悲しむか➡
わかってんのか！ ｵｶｯﾊﾟ!!
You're okay with Ms. Ketsuno crying?!
結野ｱﾅが泣いてもいいｱﾙか！
ﾌﾌ… ﾃﾒｴ 最初から
ｵﾚに仕えるつもりなんか➡
You never had any intention of
letting me order you around.
なかったんじゃねえか｡
まぁ いいさ｡
Oh well.
I'm not used to having people
serve me anyway.
人に仕えられるなんざ
慣れてなくてね｡
これで自由になれた｡
Now I'm free.
Don't you understand that a bunch of
amateurs who can't use shikigami
式神も呼べぬ
素人が行ったところで➡
血の雨が降るだけというのが
わからんか｡
would be reduced to a rain of blood?
Fine by me.
結構なことじゃねえか｡
こんな天気だ
血に濡れようが雨に濡れようが➡
Look at this weather.
Not much difference if it's
blood instead of water.
たいして変わりゃしねえだろ｡
Spring showers, fall showers,
rain of blood...
春雨だろうが秋雨だろうが
血の雨だろうが➡
濡れて参ってやるよ｡
I'm willing to stand in any of those.
だが…｡
But...
I'm done standing in a girl's tears.
女の涙に濡れるのは
もう ごめんだ｡
As I said...
(外道丸)言ったでござんしょ｡
A shikigami is always judging its master.
式神は主を常に見定めていると｡
その言葉 待ってたでやんす｡
I've been waiting for those words.
Master Gintoki, I accept you.
銀時様 認めたでやんす｡
あなたが あっしの…｡
You are my second master.
もう１人の主でござんす｡
これより あなたの命は
いかなる無理難題とて➡
From now on, I will carry out
your every command,
必ず あっしが
やり遂げてみせましょう｡
no matter how difficult it may be.
I shall protect you from bullets
and the elements.
いかなる弾丸風雨の中とて➡
あっしが あなたを
お護りしましょう｡
だから 銀時様 どうか一緒に➡
So Master Gintoki...
Please assist me in helping
Lady Christel.
ｸﾘｽﾃﾙ様を
救ってくれるでござんすか｡
あぁ 言われなくても そうするさ｡
You didn't need to ask.
But in return, skip the
master-servant crap.
だが その代わり➡
主従だの何だの無しだ
面倒くさい｡
Too much of a pain.
それから 銀時様はやめろ｡
And don't call me Master Gintoki.
Call me President.
社長と呼んでくれ｡
Pachi-boy, let's get going!
ぱっつぁん 私たちも行くｱﾙよ｡
待って！
Wait!
We can't summon shikigami or anything!
ﾎﾞｸら 式神も
何も呼び出せないけど➡
Are we really going to be okay?
本当に大丈夫かな!?
小さいこと 気にすんな！
Don't sweat the small stuff!
Small stuff?!
小さいことって
式神ﾀｯｸﾞﾏｯﾁとか言ってたよね!?
Isn't this a shikigami tag match?!
You don't need to worry!
心配いらないね
式神は いなくても➡
We don't have any shikigami,
but we still have familiar spirits!
使い魔みたいなのは いるｱﾙ｡
えっ どこに!?
Huh?! Where?!
え？
Huh?
So you've come, Seimei...
(道満)来たか 清明｡
１人で来るとは殊勝なことだな｡
I praise you for coming alone.
I can handle you myself.
(清明)ﾜｼ１人で十分｡
Simple as that.
そう踏んだだけの話｡
ﾌﾝｯ 減らず口を｡
Hah, you never shut up.
道満 ﾜｼが勝てばｸﾘｽﾃﾙに
手を出さないというのは…｡
Doman, if I win, you will stop
interfering with Christel...
Unlike you, the Shirino clan
keeps its promises.
巳厘野衆は
ｷｻﾏらと違って約束は護るさ｡
清明 お天気戦争は
ほぼ決着がついていた｡
Seimei, the weather war was all but over.
なのに なぜｵﾚが
わざわざ決戦をしこんだが➡
Yet do you know why I would bother
challenging you to a contest?!
わかるか!?
ﾊﾊﾊ それは このｵﾚの強さを
お前に見せつけるためよ！
To show you my strength!
I will destroy your pride
ｷｻﾏのﾌﾟﾗｲﾄﾞをｽﾞﾀｽﾞﾀに引き裂き➡
so you can die in despair!
絶望のうちに死に追いやるためよ｡
Seimei, ever since that day,
清明 ｵﾚはあの日から➡
ｷｻﾏら兄妹に復讐することだけを
考えて生きてきた！
I have lived solely for the sake of
revenge against you siblings!
Focused only on the moment when
I would tear the two of you apart,
ｷｻﾏたちを引き裂く
その瞬間だけを思い➡
as I sharpened my claws
in the darkness!
憎しみの闇の中で
爪を研ぎ続けてきた！
And that time has finally come!
それが 今このときだ！
The long weather war will finally end!
長きにわたった お天気戦争は
今をもって終わりを告げ…｡
Who are you?!
何者だ!?
Hey! Walk faster, shikigami!
ｵﾗ さっさと歩け 式神｡
ﾋｨ～ 何でこんなことに…｡
How did this happen?
Ah! Sorry about being late!
あの 遅れてすみません｡
Is this where the world martial
arts tournament is being held?!
天下一武闘会
会場は ここですか!?
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
Pandemonium...
Pandemonium-san...
Pandemonium-san!
Pandemonium-san!!
The next episode...
"Not Losing to the Storm."
[Shinpachi and Kagura enter round one of
the Shikigami Tag Team Mystic Deathmatch!]
["Deathmatch" means if you lose, you die.
Shikigami Shinpachi dies for love...?!]
[See you next time.]